Inventory of the Larry Eigner Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Additional Material: Preliminary Inventory, Series 8
  - Joseph Eigner: Correspondence of Larry Eigner to Joseph and Janet Eigner, circa 1963 - 1987. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Many running to multiple pages and including copies of his poetry. Some of the letters are typed on paper scraps, backs of envelopes, and the reverse of programs. Also includes 4 postcards, and a census of letters and correspondence between the evaluator, Irving P. Leif and Richard Eigner. TLS, 14 letters, (27p.) to Joseph and Janet Eigner, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner). TLS, 1p., September 5, 1978, to "Children," signed "Mom" (Eigner).
  - Joseph Eigner: Correspondence to Joseph Eigner, circa 1967 - 75. Includes 9 letters, 3 from Richard Eigner. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Undated letters to Richard and Beverly Eigner, 23 letters (36p.) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Also includes TLS, 1p. to "Children" Signed "Mom" (Eigner) and typed notes (carbon) and poetry on odd papers.
  - Folder 7 - 1960, TLS, 2p. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    To "Richie" (Eigner) November 12, 1960 Signed in type "Larry" (Eigner).
  - Folder 8 - 1960 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    TLS, 2p. on "Mrs. Israel Eigner" stationary, November 25, 1960, signed "Dad"; TLS, 2p. to "Richie" (Eigner), November 30, 1960, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 2p. to "Richie" (Eigner), August 19, 1960, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 4p. to "Richie" (Eigner), December 18, 1960, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner).
  - Folder 9 - 1961 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    TLS, 2p. to "Richie" (Eigner), March 17, 1961, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 2p. to "Richie" (Eigner), August 10, 1961, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 1p. on bookmark to "Richie" (Eigner), December 15, 1960, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner).
  - Folder 10 - 1962 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    TLS, 2p. to "Richie" (Eigner), April 26, 1962, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 2p. to "Richie" (Eigner), May 24, 1962, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 2p. to "Richie" (Eigner), May 28, 1962, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 2p. to "Richie" (Eigner), June 9, 1962, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); Postcard, 1p. to "Richie" (Eigner), December 18, 1962, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner).
  - Folder 11 - 1963 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    TLS, 11 letters, (30p.) to Richie and Beverly Eigner, 1963, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS (Carbon), 3p. to "Sirs," March 6, 1963, signed "A resident of Swampscott, Mass." (Larry Eigner); Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages (Carbon), 6p.
  - Folder 12 - 1964 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    TLS, 10 letters, (27p.) to Richie and Beverly Eigner, 1964, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 1p. to "Editors," February 28, 1964, signed in type "Larry Eigner;" Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages (Carbon), 6p.
  - Folder 13 - 1965 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    TLS, 22 letters, (50p.) to Richie and Beverly (Eigner), 1965, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); Postcards, 4p. to "Richie" (Eigner) 1965 signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 1p., June 15, 1965, signed "Raymond;" Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages (Carbon), 1p.; Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 1p.; TLS (Carbon), 1p., December 29, 1965, signed "Alfred E. Borneman;" TLS, 1p. to "Stuart," January 7, 1965, signed in type "Larry Eigner".
  - Folder 14 - 1966 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Housing Questionnaire, 2p.; TLS, 19 letters, (40p.) to Richie and Beverly (Eigner) 1966, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); Postcards, 3p. to "Richie" (Eigner), 1966; TLS, 3p. signed "Bill;" TLS (Carbon), 1p., November 13, 1966, Re: Up/Down/Walls, signed in type. "Stuart" (Fulcrum Press); Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 12p.; Typed (Poetry) Manuscript (Carbon), 21p. (Labeled #6 - #26).
  - Folder 15 - 1967 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    TLS, 15 letters, (29p.) to Richie and Beverly (Eigner), 1967,signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 1p., November 21, 1967, signed "Richard" (Eigner); Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 15p.
  - Folder 16 - 1967 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    TLS, 11 letters, (18p.) to Richie and Beverly (Eigner), 1967, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); Typed (Prose) Manuscript (Carbon), 10p. "Communality, among other things;" Typed (Poetry) Manuscript (Carbon), 4p. "ties/sleep/ers;" Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 3p.
  - Folder 17 - 1968 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    TLS, 13 letters, (29p.) to Richie and Beverly (Eigner), 1968, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 1p. November 6, 1968 signed "Don Allen" ALS, 1p. to "Beverly" (Eigner) February 2, 1968. signed "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 1p. on "Mrs. Israel Eigner" stationary. November 15, 1968 signed "Mom;" Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 7p.
  - Folder 18 - 1968 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    TLS, 5 letters, (12p.) to Richie and Beverly (Eigner), 1968, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 9p
  - Folder 19 - 1969 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    TLS, 11 letters, (20p.) to Richie and Beverly (Eigner), 1969, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 3p.
  - Folder 20 - 1970 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    TLS, 28 letters, (61p.) and 1 postcard Richie and Beverly (Eigner) 1970, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS(carbon),1p., September 15, 1970, signed in type "Alexadra Mason;" Typed list, 1p. "Eigner Bibliography December 1968," TLS, 1p., signed "Michael" (McClure); ALS, 1p., June, 1970, signed "Peter Boffey;" TLS, 2p.(Photocopy) July 28, 1970. To "Willis H." signed "Larry Eigner" ALS, 4p. August 7, 1970. signed "Jan" Newsclipping(Photocopy), November 19, 1970. Marblehead Reporter Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 35 Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages(Photocopy), 25 Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 2p. "Integration, Interchange".
  - Folder 21 - 1971 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    TLS, 28 letters, (53p.) and 2 postcards to Richie and Beverly (Eigner) 1971, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 24p.; Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages(Carbon), 4p. Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages(Photocopy), 33p.
  - Folder 22 - 1972 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    TLS, 20 letters, (39p.) and 1 postcard to Richie and Beverly (Eigner) 1972, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); ALS, 1p. on Manroot letterhead, May 29, 1972, signed "Paul Mariah;" TLS, 1p. on Noel Pearson Management Ltd. Stationary. May 1, 1972. signed in type "Noel Pearson" w/ enclosed letter from Christy Brown, 1p. Contract, 1p. Qyez Mach 30, 1972. Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages(Photocopy), 94p. Typed (Prose) Manuscript (Photocopy), 8p. Supplementary Statement #1-3.
  - Folder 23 - 1973 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    TLS, 20 letters, (39p.) and 1 postcard to Richie and Beverly (Eigner) 1973, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); TLS, 3p. to Richie and Beverly (Eigner) 1973 signed in type "Larry" (Eigner) on reverse of ALS, 1p. to Richie and Beverly (Eigner) signed "Joe" Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages(Photocopy), 7p.
  - Folder 24 - 1974 through 1977 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    TLS, 17 letters, (47p.) and 1 postcard to Richie and Beverly (Eigner) 1974 - 1977, signed in type "Larry" (Eigner); Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 4p; Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages (Photocopy), 5p.
  - Folder 25 - Larry Eigner Poetry (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages (Carbon), 117p; Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages (Photocopy), 52p.
  - Folder 26 - Larry Eigner Poetry (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Typed (Poetry) Manuscript pages, 57p. (some typed on scraps of paper and backs of envelopes, some holograph notation)
  - Folder 27 Juvenalia of Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 3)
    TLS, 3 letters on Child Life Stationary 1937/1939; Child Life, Vol. 16, #9 September, 1937, (Contains prize-winning poem by Larry Eigner, "When All Sleep", p. 426), partial, torn copy; Child Life, Vol. 18, #10 October, 1939 (Contains letter by Larry Eigner, p. 474); Child Life, Vol. 19, #1 January, 1940 (Contains short story by Larry Eigner, p. 40); Hadassah News-ette, Vol. 2, #9. May, 1937 (Contains poem by Larry Eigner) - 2 copies; Boston C. P. News, Vol. 1, #4. January, 1950 (Contains poem by Larry Eigner), Poems by Laurence Joel Eigner, June, 1941; Newsclipping, Salem Evening News, February 14, 1948 (Contains poem by Larry Eigner, "Cloud Sculptures"); Newsclipping, (Contains poem by Larry Eigner, "Candle"); ALS, 2p. on notecard w/ envelope, November 27, 1938, re: proposed publication of "When All Sleep" signed "Eillen Fulton"
  - Folder 28 Cards and correspondence to Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 4)
    From a class of French school children who read his poems in class.
  - Folder 29 Correspondence to Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Including 10 letters and 2 postcards from Jack Collom.
  - Folder 30 - Andrea Wyatt Correspondence to Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 6)
    From Andrea Wyatt (author of bibliography and poet), circa 1969 - 1971. Includes TLS, 33 letters w/ poetry, 30p. to Larry Eigner, TLS, 1p. to Richard Eigner and 1 broadside dedicated to Larry Eigner. 3 letters have Eigner poetry on reverse. Paper is heavily handled.
  - Folder 31 - Dan Propper Correspondence to Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 7)
    From Dan Propper, poet, circa 1974. Includes 2 letters and 4 broadsides.
  - Folder 32 - Sam Charters Correspondence to Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 8)
    From Sam Charters(Portents), circa 1968 - 1973. Includes 12 letters (14p.), some w/ Larry Eigner poetry typed on reverse. Paper is heavily handled.
  - Folder 33 - Bill Costley Correspondence to Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 9)
    From Bill Costley, circa 1969- 74, Includes 4 letters w/ posters and poetry.
  - Folder 34 - Peter Gannick Correspondence to Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 10)
    From Peter Gannick, circa 1970 - 71. Includes 21 letters and 1 postcard.
  - Folder 35 - Other Correspondence to Larry Eigner (Box 23, Folder 11-12)
    From poets and publishers of his work, circa 1959 - 71. Major correspondents (one letter from each unless noted) include Hugh Fox; Blaz(Open Skull Press); The Sumac Press; 3 letters from Cid Corman (w/ photocopy of Eigner reply); Christopher Waylen; Michael McClure; Montgomery Tyson; 3 letters from Richard Peabody(Gargoyle); 3 letters from Jim Koller; The restau press; John Taggart; 1 postcard from Gilbert Sorrentino; Jackson Mac Low; Fred R. Fry; Bruce Andrews; 3 letters from Anne Mazonson; 3 letters from Kris Hemensley; 3 letters from Stuart Montgomery (The Fulcrum Press); 5 letters from Ian (Tetrad Press); 5 letters from John Martin (Black Sparrow Press); 3 letters from Anne Mazonson; 3 postcards from Terence Inman; and others. Approximately 110 letters and 16 postcards. Also contains envelope w/ saved addresses of correspondents. Paper is heavily handled.
  - Folder 36 - Miscellaneous papers (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Flyers, circulars, programs, photocopies, newsclippings, typed (poetry) pages from correspondents.
  - Folder 37 - Newspaper articles (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Includes articles about Larry Eigner, publications of his work and reviews of his poetry. Approximately 40 pieces.
  - Folder 38 Typed (Poetry) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Manuscript(Carbon), 39p., High Life from the Hospital Bedrooms; TLS(photocopy), 2p., September 5, 1962, To "M. Ferlengh," signed in Type " Larry Eigner".
  - Folder 39 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Typed (Poetry) Manuscript (Photocopy) pages, approximately 175p., Poems March 29, 1969, #300 - #471, some w/holograph notations; Typed (Poetry) Manuscript (Photocopy) pages, 3p., (#547 - 549).
  - Folder 40 - Manuscripts (copies) (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Typed (Prose) Manuscript (Photocopy), 6p., "Institution" - 3 copies; Typed (Prose) Manuscript (Photocopy), 3p. "Quiet;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript (Photocopy), 5p., "Qt" - 2 copies; Typed (Prose) Manuscript (Photocopy), 2p., "Globe;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript (Photocopy), 8p., title page missing
  - Folder 41 - Manuscripts of Prose Works (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 17p., "Car;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 5p., "Flight;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 8p., "Control;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 7p., "Table Talk and Rides;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 9p., "The Small Man;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 4p., "Ball Game;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 4p., "What Comes;" Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 3p., "The car parked with an amount of effort..."
  - Folder 42 Typed (Prose) (Box 24, Folder 7)
    Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 10p. "The Poetry of Larry Eigner" by Janet Eigner; Typed (Prose) Manuscript (Photocopy), 19p., "A Feeling of Eternity: Larry Eigner: The Man and his Poetry" by Joan Avioli; Typed (Prose) Manuscript, 16p., "Another Time in Fragments" author uncredited.
  - Folder 43 Typed (Poetry) (Box 24, Folder 8)
    Typed (Poetry) Manuscript (carbon) approximately 100p., Another Time in Fragments w/ holograph notations by Larry Eigner; TLS (Carbon), 2p. to "Donald Hutter," November 5, 1965, signed in type "Larry Eigner;" TLS (Photocopy), 1p. to "Stuart," January 7, 1965, signed in type "Larry Eigner"
  - Folder 44 Typed (Poetry) (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Manuscript (photocopy), approximately 100p., Another Time in Fragments
  - Folder 45 Typed (Poetry) (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Larry Eigner Manuscripts (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
    Typed (Poetry) Manuscript (Photocopy) pages, approximately 900p., poems from February 16, 1964 - December 20, 1970.
  - Larry Eigner Manuscripts (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Typed (Poetry) Manuscript (Photocopy) pages, approximately 100p., poems from December 20, 1971 - January 19, 1971.
  - Notebook, and Manuscript (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Notebok Typed (Poetry); Manuscript (Photocopy) pages, 190p. #1 - 190, June 6, 1966 - April 29, 1968, some w/ holograph notations.
  - Audio- tape (Box 26, Folder 3)
    1/4 inch reel to reel tape, 7 inch reel "Writers and Writing: David Gitin interviews Larry Eigner;" Cassette Tape, "Jack Foley interviews Larry Eigner on KPFA," March 9, 1994; Cassette Tape, "Larry Eigner Poems;" Cassette Tape, "K. Robinson, R. Silliman, Robert Creeley re: Larry Eigner KALW" Summer, 1993; Cassette Tape, Laurence Henny film; Cassette Tape, Larry Eigner Poems
  - Color Slides (Box 26, Folder 4)
    20 35mm color slides of paintings.
  - Manuscripts, Poetry, Correspondence. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Folder 46 - English 101 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Course taken by distance from the University of Chicago, Instructor Catherine Q. Baskerville, September 15, 1945. Assignments completed by Larry Eigner and typed by his mother -17 typed assignments, (120p.) w/ workbook.
  - Folder 47 - English 130 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Course taken by distance from the University of Chicago, Instructor Frances S. Nipp, April 1946. Assignments completed by Larry Eigner and typed by his mother - 16 typed assignments, 160p. w/ workbook.
  - Folder 48 - Penny Poems (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Penny Poems, incomplete run # 33 - 173 (1959 to 1961) includes "Hewings" #71, 1959 by Larry Eigner.Transcript
  - Folder 49 Transcript (Photocopy), 56p. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Poetry reading film by Laurence Henny, Tape One.
  - Folder 50 Transcript (Photocopy), 40p. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Poetry reading film by Laurence Henny, Tape Two.
  - Faust Foutu by Robert Duncan (w/ holograph annotations by Eigner), 2 copies (Box 27, Folder 7-8)
  - Periodicals (Box 27, Folder 9-17)
    Once Brewed: Buck Rock Poets, 1959, 7p; J.(no date); J.(no date); Panjandrum; Miam #2; Miam #3; The Worm in the Rain; Tottel's #7: David Gittin; Tottel's 15: Larry Eigner; tel-let 41, There's a Season by Larry Eigner, 1995; tel-let 5, cloudy all right by Larry Eigner, 1990; Environment, October 1969.
  - Two Bezoars by Eigner and Grenier. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Works by other authors (copies) (Box 28, Folder 1-6)
    The Oriental trial and Punishment of Bishop O'Malley, 21p, and, What Clara Saw in the Crystal Ball by Jerome Weinstein, 13p; A cunt not fit for the Queen by Paul Buck, 52p; Braille Landscape: Poems by Howard Schwartz; Script (untitled); Daytripper ragas by Bill Costley; An Introduction to Jazz by Paul Nossiter, 116p. (Mimeograph copy).
  - Look at the Park (Box 28, Folder 7)
    By Larry Eigner Swampscott, MA: Eigner, 1958.
  - Broadside: Jupiter C for the Missile Age (Box 28, Folder 8)
    4 poems by Kenneth McRobbie, 1958.
  - Programs: Matrix/Berkeley 159 Pacific Film Archive June 1993, 5 copies. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Yearbook: Metropolitan School - 1971, "All Brightness Springs". (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Books (Box 28, Folder 11-17)
    A Bibliography of Works by Larry Eigner (1937 - 1969) By Andrea Wyatt Berkeley: Oyez, 1970 - 9 copies; Indian Journals, March 1962 - May 1963 by Allen Ginsberg San Francisco: City Lights, 1970; Rare Angel by Michael McClure Los Angeles: Black Sparrow Press, 1974; The Year as Catches: First Poems ((1939 - 1946) by Robert Duncan Berkeley: Oyez, 1966; The Charm by Robert Creeley San Francisco: Four Seasons Foundation, 1969; Straight Hearts' Delight: Love Poems and Selected Letters by Winston Leyland San Francisco: Gay Sunshine Press, 1980 (Autographed); Living Dying: Poems of Cid Corman New York: New Directions, 1970.
  - Notebooks (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
    Humanities 2A: Course taken by distance from the University of Chicago, Instructor John C. Pletz, October 21, 1947. Assignments completed by Larry Eigner and typed by his mother - 23 assignments, 137p; Humanities 2B: Course taken by distance from the University of Chicago. Assignments completed by Larry Eigner and typed by his mother - 23 typed assignments, 169p; Psychology 201: Course taken by distance from the University of Chicago, Instructor LeRoy S. Burwen. October 21, 1947. Assignments completed by Larry Eigner and typed by his mother - 30 assignments, 218p.
  - Correspondence & Poetry for Arnold Goldman. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts:Larry's Eyes by Larry Eigner and Jack Foley, typed manuscript, 2pp. w/title page. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript, The Children by Gil Ott (Box 30, Folder 3)
    Typed manuscript (photocopy), 12pp. w/title page & letter.
  - Typed Poetry (Box 30, Folder 4)
    #444 September 29, 1970 & #840 February 20, 1974.
  - Copies of Eigner poetry, (carbons, photocopy, facsimile) some with holograph notes by Eigner, well-thumbed, torn, 85pp. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 6)
    4 Aerogrammes (photocopies) from "Corman" 1989-1990; 1 typed letter from Eigner to "Richie" 13 December 1964 on typed page of poetry (carbon); 1 postcard from Black Sparrow Press w/ holograph notes in pencil by Eigner; 1 TLS, March 4, 1965, signed Daniel Zimmerman; 1 ALS, April 1, 1967, signed Peter Jay.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 7)
    3 Flyers for Larry Eigner poetry programs; Broadside, clouding by Larry Eigner, Portents #10; Publications announcements, Singing Horse Press.
  - Correspondence. Letters to Eigner. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    "dar" = Nevada Tattoo Press, date obscured, APC, N/c; Paul Auster, 1977; Paul Auster, 9 October1975; Paul Auster, 22 August 1974; George Bowering, September 19, 1962; Gene Fowler, Undated; Arnold Goldman; Daphne Marlatt, August 6, 1972; Randy Roark, 1995; Bud Samiljan, August 4, 1977.
  - Correspondence. Letters to Eigner. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    John Marton, 1993; Mernard Press Pub, APCS, 1975; Lita Hornick, TNS, 1963; Jan & Joe, TLS, 2pp. 1983; Larry Eigner typed poem, as submitted (?), February 23, 1965; Larry Eigner typed poem, July 6, 1971.: "No More Horn;" James Weil TPCS, 1982; Brian. Typed poem "For Larry" inscribed.
  - Correspondence. Letters to Eigner. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Eigner Correspondence from boxes from his library.